girlsnotbrides.org 2018-12-29

# Privacy Policy - Girls Not Brides

Preservation of your privacy is important to Girls Not Brides and we are committed to letting you know how we use your personal information and using it responsibly. This privacy policy (“the Privacy Policy”) should be read in conjunction with the www.girlsnotbrides.org Website Terms and Conditions.

The website www.girlsnotbrides.org (“the Website”), is owned and operated by Girls Not Brides: The Global Partnership to End Child Marriage, a company limited by guarantee registered in England and Wales (Reg No.: 8570751) and a registered charity in England and Wales (Reg No: 1154230).

References to ‘Girls Not Brides‘, ‘we’, ‘us’ or ‘our’ in this Privacy Policy are references to Girls Not Brides: The Global Partnership to End Child Marriage.

  1. **When do we collect your personal information**
  2. **What personal information do we collect**
  3. **Our use of your personal information**
  4. **Lawful grounds**
  5. **Do we share your personal information?**
  6. **International Data Transfers**
  7. **Security**
  8. **How long do we keep your personal information?**
  9. **Children**
  10. **Cookies**
  11. **Your rights and preferences**
  12. **Changes to this Privacy Policy**
  13. **Other websites**
  14. **Contract us**

  1. **When do we collect your personal information**

1.1    We collect personal information from you when you:

  * sign-up for our newsletter(s);
  * share information, including but not limited to information about yourself through the Website;
  * enquire about our services and/or about Girls Not Brides;
  * register your organisation as a member of Girls Not Brides;
  * register for any of our mailing lists or events through the Website; and/or
  * contact us through the Website.

1.2    We collect your personal information from your employer when they apply for or are a member of Girls Not Brides and provide your details to us so that you and your organisation may benefit from membership e.g. to be educated and updated about opportunities to influence others. For instance, this is the case if you are the Head of the organisation, the membership contact point, the advocacy and policy contact point, the communications and media contact point or the programmatic contact point.

  2. **What personal information do we collect**

2.1  The personal information we collect may include but is not limited to the following information about you:

  * Your name (including your first names and surname);
  * Your email address and Skype ID;
  * Your telephone number(s) (including your mobile telephone number);
  * Your language(s); and
  * The name of the organisation you work with or are employed by and your job title.

2.2 We also collect certain personal information automatically from you when you visit our website. This includes information about your computer/ mobile device and your visits to and use of this website, including, for example, your IP address and geographical location.

2.3 We do not intentionally collect your sensitive personal data (also known as special categories of personal data). In exceptional instances we collect sensitive personal data about the beneficiaries which our members support and, in such circumstances, we shall obtain explicit consent from the beneficiaries in order to use their sensitive personal data (such explicit consent can always be withdrawn).

2.4 We may also collect additional information about your organisation’s programmes and where your organisation works but this will mostly not be personal information.

  3. **Our use of your personal information**

3.1    Your personal information will only be used by us to:

  * process your requests;
  * process an application for membership;
  * send you news updates by email;
  * respond to your questions or comments;
  * provide or administer activities relating to our services e.g. referrals to other members of our network or NGOs who can assist with your programme;
  * provide you with information relating to the Website, Girls Not Brides or our services, or that we feel may be of interest to you;
  * maintain our organisational records; and
  * carry out research or prepare reports.

3.2    If you do not want to receive information from us please contact us by email at info@girlsnotbrides with the word “unsubscribe” in the subject field. If you only wish to unsubscribe from one of our services, please specify this in the email.

  4. **Lawful grounds**

We are required to rely on one or more lawful grounds to collect and use the personal information that we have outlined above. We consider the grounds listed below to be relevant:

  1. **Consent**

Where you have provided your consent for our use of your personal information in a certain way, for example where we ask for your consent to send you our daily digest email.

  1. **Legal obligation**

Where the processing of your personal information is necessary for us to comply with a legal obligation to which we are subject.

  1. **Contractual relationship**

Where it is necessary for us to process your personal information in order to perform a contract to which you are a party (or to take steps at your request prior to entering a contract). For example, where your organisation becomes a member of our network it enters into a contract with us.

  1. **Legitimate interests**

We rely on this basis where applicable law allows us to collect and use personal information for our legitimate interests and the use of your personal information is fair, balanced, and does not unduly impact your rights. For instance, it is in our legitimate interest to process personal data on the employees of our member organisations in order to inform such employees of of new learning about child marriage, developments in the field, fundraising opportunities and opportunities to join events, webinars, etc. to increase their capacity or knowledge.

  5. **Do we share your personal information?**

4.1    Any personal information that you provide when you use the Website may be shared with third parties in these circumstances:

4.1.1    providers of support services to Girls Not Brides but only if the sharing of your personal information is necessary to carry out such support services and such third parties are required to use any personal information they receive in accordance with our instructions; and/ or

4.1.2    companies or organisations that are connected to or affiliated to Girls Not Brides (e.g. other members of our network) when in line with the purposes set out in section 3 above.

We additionally reserve the right to disclose your personal information to third parties:

  1. in the event that we buy or sell any business or assets, in which case we will disclose your personal information to the prospective buyer or seller or such business or assets;
  2. if substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, personal information held by us may be one of the transferred assets;
  3. for auditing purposes e.g. finance audits where we employ chartered accountants;
  4. if we are under any legal or regulatory obligation to do so; and
  5. in connection with any legal proceedings or prospective legal proceedings, in order to establish, exercise or defend our legal rights.

4.2    We do not sell or lease your personal information to any third parties.

  6. **International Data Transfers**

6.1 Certain countries have rules around the transfer of personal information and require us to ensure that personal information remains protected according to appropriate standards. For instance, certain countries outside of the UK or EU have a lower standard of protection for personal information, including lower security protections. In such cases, where your personal information is transferred, stored, and/or otherwise processed outside the UK or EU in a country which does not offer an equivalent standard of protection to the UK or EU, we will take all reasonable steps necessary to ensure that the recipient implements appropriate safeguards designed to protect your personal information (for instance, entering into the standard contractual clauses or relying on the Privacy Shield).

6.2 If you have any questions about the transfer of your personal information, please contact us using the details at _section 14_.

  7. **Security**

5.1    We will take reasonable precautions to prevent the loss, misuse or alteration of personal information you give us.

5.2    Communications in connection with the Website may be sent by us by e-mail. For ease of use and compatibility, communications will not be sent to you in an encrypted form unless we specifically agree to do so and you provide the certification to enable us to communicate with you in that way. E-mail unless encrypted is not a fully secure means of communication. Whilst we endeavour to keep our systems and communications protected against tracking viruses and other harmful effects we cannot bear responsibility for all communications being virus-free.

  8. **How long do we keep your personal information?**

** ** 8.1 We will keep your personal information for as long as necessary:

  * To comply with any statutory or regulatory requirements we are subject to under applicable law;
  * To fulfil the purposes for which the personal information was collected; or
  * To defend our or a third party’s legal rights. For instance, we will generally remove your personal information from our records six years after the date that it was collected since that is the period of limitation for bringing actions against us under UK law

8.2 If you have any questions about our retention periods, please contact us using the details at section 14 below.

  9. **Children**

9.1. Our website is not intended to be used by individuals who are under the age of thirteen (13). If you are under the age of thirteen (13) please do not provide personal information to us or through our website.

9.2 If you are aged between thirteen (13) and eighteen (18) years of age, you can only use our Website with the consent of your parent or guardian.

  10. **Cookies**

6.1    A “cookie” is a small text file that is placed on a website user’s computer hard drive by a website. There are several types of cookie.

6.2    The types of cookie we use are “session cookies”, which keep track of information you have entered or looked at as you travel from page to page in the Website. These cookies have a short lifetime and expire within a short time of you leaving the Website. We do not use other types of cookie that track your internet activity after leaving the Website.

6.3    We use cookies to tell whether you have logged in to the Website, to see how you are viewing the Website and how you navigate around the Website, and to assist us in providing the services we offer.

6.4    Internet browsers normally accept cookies by default. However, it is possible to set an internet browser to reject cookies.

6.5    The use of cookies helps us to assess, operate and improve the Website and to operate it effectively.  You can find out more information about cookies here:  http://www.allaboutcookies.org

  11. **Your rights and preferences**

We may contact you by telephone, email, text, social media or other electronic means depending on the communication preferences you have previously indicated.

Where we rely on your consent to use your personal information, you have the right to withdraw your consent.

When we use your personal information you have the right to:

  1. Ask us for **confirmation** of what personal information we hold about you, and to request **access** to a copy of that information. If we are satisfied that you have a right to see this personal information, and we are able to confirm your identity, we will provide you with this personal information.
  2. Request that we **delete** the personal information we hold about you, as far as we are legally required to do so
  3. Ask that we **correct** any personal information that we hold about you which you believe to be inaccurate.
  4. **Object** to the processing of your personal information where we: (i) process on the basis of the legitimate interests ground; (ii) use the personal information for direct marketing; or (iii) use the personal information for statistical purposes.
  5. Ask for the **provision** of your personal information in a machine-readable format to either yourself or a third party, provided that the personal information in question has been provided to us by you, and is being processed by us: (i) in reliance on your consent; or (ii) because it is necessary for the performance of a contract to which you are party; _and_ in either instance, we are processing it using automated means.
  6. Ask for processing of your personal information to be **restricted** if there is disagreement about its accuracy or legitimate usage.

If you decide you do not want to receive any further emails from Girls Not Brides, please tell us and we will remove you from the mailing list. At any point you can request to unsubscribe form our mailing by contacting us using the details listed at _section 14 below_.

Please note that where you ask us to delete your personal information we will maintain a skeleton record comprising your name and contact details to ensure that we do not inadvertently contact you in the future.  We may also need to retain some financial records for statutory purposes.

**Please note that** you also have the right to lodge a complaint with your local data protection authority. In the UK this is the Information Commissioner’s Office at [www.ico.org.uk/concerns](http://www.ico.org.uk/concerns). In France this is the Commission nationale de l’informatique et des libertés at [www.cnil.fr](http://www.cnil.fr/).

If you would like us to exercise any of your rights, then please contact us at [info@GirlsNotBrides.org](mailto:info@GirlsNotBrides.org)

  12. **Changes to this Privacy Policy**

We may update this Privacy Policy by posting a new version on this website. If we update this Privacy Policy in a way that significantly changes how we use your personal information, we will bring these changes to your attention. Otherwise, we recommend that you periodically review this Privacy Policy to be aware of any other revisions.

  13. **Other websites**

Links within our website to other websites are not covered by this Privacy Policy. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of linked web sites. Please review the privacy notices of such websites.

  14. **Contact us**

You can also contact us if you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or our treatment of your personal information:

Email:  **info@GirlsNotBrides.org**

Telephone:  **0203-725 5858**

Post: **FAO  Charlotte Janiszewsk**i

Dated: **22 May 2018**

Version 2

This Privacy Policy should be read in conjunction with the [Website Terms and Conditions](https://www.girlsnotbrides.org/terms-conditions/) for [www.girlsnotbrides.org](https://www.girlsnotbrides.org/ "Girls not Brides")
